

Kate McMahan

((<u>|</u>

609-613-1139



mcmahank.myportfolio.com



kate.mcdesigns@gmail.com



In linkedin.com/in/kate-mcdesigns/



Profile

Philadelphia-based UX Designer, with experience in art direction and a great passion for learning that stems from a background of teaching/living in diverse cultures. Instills the learning cycle in all designs. Excells at finding new angles to look at problems, asking thoughtful questions, and making improvements along the way.



Education

UX Design Certification

2018-2019

Career Foundry

UX Designer

 10 month project-based immersion program for UX Designers, focusing on data and research-driven design, methodology, IA, wireframing, and rapid prototyping.

Bachelor of Arts in Japanese

2010-2014

Elizabethtown College

Magna Cum Laude, East Asian Studies and Art minor.



Experience

ESL Teacher

2018-present

VIPKid | West Chester, PA

- Independently contracted ESL teacher for a China based e-learning platform.
- Taught over 400 classes with an average parent feedback score of 4.99 out of 5 (based on 110 reviews).

ESL Teacher

2014-2017

Kuriyama Board of Education | Kuriyama, Hokkaido

- Taught English as a Second Language (ESL) at the pre-school, elementary school, junior high school, and adult level.
- Developed curriculum and materials for two elementary schools.

Publications Designer

2015-2016

HAJET | Kuriyama, Hokkaido

- Designed a monthly e-publication for the Hokkaido Association for Japan Exchange and Teaching (HAJET).
- Collaborated with over 10 foreign artists and photographers residing in Hokkaido prefecture.

Convention Vice President, Art Director

2012-2014

Jaycon | Elizabethtown, PA

- Collaborated, corresponded with, and directly managed over 30 independent artists and dealers.
- Designed logo, event booklet, badges, and other branding.

Skills

Competitive Analysis User Research

User Interviews Personas User Flows Information Architecture Wireframing Prototyping Usability Testing Graphic Design



lools

Invision Sketch Balsamiq Photoshop InDesign Illustrator Abobe XD Basic HTML/CSS



Languages

English (Native) Japanese

(conversational proficiency)